What is MTF or Margin Trade Funding?
MTF and how can you use it in your
intraday trading as well as delivery
trading. If you
want, you can do BTST in it for delivery or
you can also hold your shares with this margin for long term.
I have divided this video into some parts. First of all,
I will talk about
what is MTF, then we will talk about its margin,
then how much interest
rate do you charge in it, if you hold it
for intraday or for a day
or for a few days, then how much
interest is charged on that, then we will
talk about its charges, what are the charges, then
after that we will understand by taking an example and
in the last we will discuss an FAQ in
which I will mention all your questions which people
always ask me,
so let's start
our video. What is
MTF? Its full form is
Margin
Trade Funding.
This is ours, which we use
for intraday trading
or futures and options trading by pledging our normal shares.
This is a different kind of
funding than margin. What happens in this is that
your broker
funds your trading. For example, in my case, my
broker is currently here. So, if
I want to buy a stock and I have
less money, let's say I have
100,000 rupees, and I want to buy a stock,
whether it's for intraday, whether I
buy it today and sell it tomorrow, or if
I want to do swing trading for a few days, then
in that case, if I have a larger
trade, I can use MTF
and
take a trade of approximately 400,000 rupees.
And this remaining 300,000 rupees is
provided by your broker, that is, the money. So, you have 100,000 rupees in your account.
You can take leverage of approximately 4x the time period. The
interest rate, etc., will be discussed later.
But you can use this for swing trading,
i.e., buying today and selling tomorrow. You can
also use it for intraday.
Or if your position is getting stuck,
you can hold it for a week.  You can hold it for a month,
a year, for however long you
want. So, in a
way, you are given funding for your delivery shares by the
broker. This is called MTF
or margin trade funding. As I
told you, if
you have ₹1 lakh, then you get an extra margin of approximately ₹1 lakh and you can take a trade of ₹1 lakh,
that is, for ₹1 you get a
margin of 300 and you can take a trade of 400.
So, you get a margin of 75 rupees for the size of your
trade in the form of a loan.
Suppose you want to take a trade of ₹000, then if you have at
least ₹1000 in your account, then
you will get a margin of ₹7750. Now, is this
available on all the shares? No,
these are small shares, micro caps,
small caps, which probably do not have this.
Normally, these are more than 1000 shares
in our market.
You will find this on large stocks. If you want to see the list of the entire stock,
you will find a link in the description below to show which
stocks it is available on. Normally, this is the
500 shares of Nifty 500 and
some other shares which are more than 1000
shares. Now let's talk about the interest charged on this. There are
two
types of interest. First, understand that
if you took a trade in MTF this morning
and you reversed that trade before 3:30 in the evening,
that is,
you had only 000 in intraday, you took a trade of about 4000
and you
closed that trade before 3:30, then
you will not have to pay any interest even after taking MTF margin in intraday. This is the
first point. The second point is that
if you hold it for a day or more, then
you will have to pledge it first. The
pledging time is
between 4:00 pm to 9:00 pm, that is,  If you
took an MTF trade in the morning today,
you have to pledge it between 4 pm to 9:00 pm
and
you will be charged interest on it at the rate of 0.048 per day. That is,
if you have taken a margin of ₹1 lakh, then
you will be charged interest of ₹3.80 paise per day on it.
This is not a trade of ₹1 lakh, I am
talking about a trade of ₹1 lakh, the trade can be of ₹125000 or ₹
130000, whatever the amount you have
taken margin for, for example, if it is a trade of ₹000, then
if you are taking a margin of ₹750, then
0.43% interest is charged on that ₹750 every day,
which I told you is on
₹1 lakh, then you will be charged interest of ₹80 paise every day. It is
free for intraday. Now let's talk about the charges on this.
If you are doing intraday
trading, then you
took the trade in the morning and exited it in the evening.  If
you do this, then
your standard charges for intraday trading, ₹
0 buying, ₹ selling or whatever is on the
lower side, the
same will be levied and there will be
no interest in it and you will
not have to do any pledging if you are
taking intraday, if you are not taking intraday,
suppose you bought today and want to sell tomorrow or day after tomorrow,
then you will have to do
pledging.  Plus GST
is applicable at the time of pledging.  Plus GST is
charged while unloading. Apart from this,
all your standard delivery charges, your average
charges will be charged.
Now when you trade it, I will show you
how you can take an MTF trade.
When I show it to you,
I will also show you how
you can see the entire charges before taking the charges. So, before
covering the FQ, let me
tell you that
in the form of an example, if you want to take a trade here, then
how can you take it?
Suppose I go here in my watch list
and there is any share,
I pick any of these shares, like
I want to take a trade, for example, suppose I
pick SBI now, that I want to take a
trade in SBI, then here we go to
buy to take a trade normally, similarly
we
will click on buy here in this way and now here
you will see three options,
this is the delivery option, this is the intraday
option and this third option is
MTF, you can use it for intraday.  You
can use it for trading and also for delivery.
So I click on this.
Now, as you can see, the
price of State Bank of India is currently 801. So,
if I am buying one share here
and I have placed this limit order, then
suppose I set its price here, that when
its price reaches 800, then
I want to buy it. Now, as I
set this price of 800, okay. Now, in this
funding estimator, you will get
your complete cost analysis.
This is the important thing that you have to keep in
mind. And on this trade, you can see
how much leverage you are getting on this MTF trade. That
means, if you have 00, then
352 will provide you money. So, that much
you will get. That means you will be able to take a trade of 4452.
This is what it is telling you. So,
in this case, we click here on the
funding estimator and we see that
its  How much funds are required for this? So
here you have seen these are the charges of SBI.
You are taking one quantity, so
your buy price is 800. The trade value is also
800. Your trade type is buy in MTF.
You are taking a trade in NSC and this is an
equity trade. Now you see here
how much funds you have to invest. In this case, you have to
put approximately 228 in it, that is,
your funds will be invested at 8.46 and the
funding is giving you at 71.54.
In this case, the money i.e., approximately
5572 is giving you money. In this trade,
this amount is yours and has become margin
or leverage. So, if you hold it for one day,
you will be charged on this amount. You will
not be charged on this amount or it is your own amount, so
how much will it be charged on ₹ 72. So, here
you see your interest rate, as
I told you,
is 0.43%. So,
I told you this on 1 lakh in one day.  It will
cost you approximately ₹ 80 paise, so you
can assume it to be 4.38
paise and for 1000 you can assume it to be
approximately
0.44 i.e. 44 paise, so if
you are taking a trade of 800 then it will cost you approximately
40 to 45 paise per day,
so this is
your only cost of holding it for one day which
you are finding extra, okay, now
after this, as I have told you that
in pledging you will have to spend Rs.  Plus GST is charged
when you un-pledge,
that is, pledging, and when you go to sell,
automatic un-pledge happens. At that time also,
you think how long can you hold it?
You can hold this share as long as you wish, as
long as
you are giving this much money for it and this much money
is available in your account. Okay, these are the
charges related to it and if
you see below, these are your normal
standard charges, brokerage,
in this there is a brokerage of 24 paise on 0.03,
then there are your exchange charges,
STT, GST, SEBI charges,
IPFT, clearing charges,
stem duty, DP, most of these are
standard charges of the government,
except brokerage, you charge standard in all of these, so
your total
break even is 8168.5 paise, whereas
you are taking this at 800, you are
taking this at around 800, at 816.  Your
break-in comes here, so
you can see all these charges here and after seeing this,
I have already explained it to you here,
when you feel it is okay, you can
click on this instant buy here,
you have to check it and it
is telling you that if your MTF
pledge is not completed, if you have
not taken the MTF pledge, then on t+5 day
this will be sold and your
margin risk should remain with you at 20, if it
goes below 20 then
also it is possible that it may exit
you from this trade from your account,
so after doing this we check
and place our order of buy with margin funding,
so in this way you
can place your order, now we do not charge any
FQs or frequency, for
one day, for two days, for
10 days, for 1 year, for 10 years, there is
no holding period, as far as age is concerned, the
daily interest that I told
you will be charged till  If you have the money in your account
or you have the minimum
funding requirement of Rs. 20 in your account, then
you do
n't need to worry, you
can hold it for as long as you want. The second question is what
if I take a trade in MTF and for
some reason
forget to pledge it between 4:00 pm and 9:00 pm, then what will happen? If
you do
not pledge in MTF, then it will be considered as your normal
delivery order. In that case, if you have that much
money in your account, suppose
you took a trade of Rs. 1 lakh in total and you have Rs. 1
lakh in your account, then nothing else, it will be
considered as your normal order and
shares worth Rs. 1 lakh will come to your account in the normal DP.
But if you do not have that much money in your account, then you will be charged the
daily
interest.
If
you do not close it by the day of t + 5, then on t + 5 day,
your broker i.e. Dhan will automatically close it.  The
next question that people
ask is, well, you've explained
how to enter. After entering,
you have to pledge. What do we have to do when exiting? Do
we have to go and unpledge first?
Exiting is absolutely simple. You do
n't have to do anything just like you exit a normal share. There's
no extra step. Any
unpledged trades automatically. When you
exit that trade, your
unpledged trades automatically don't need to be taken.
Some people were asking if you
could use it for BTST. I'll
buy shares today for around 33,880 paise a day.
You'll incur daily interest.
You'll have to pledge them today.
Tomorrow, when you sell, they'll automatically unpledge. So, yes,
you can use it for BTST as well.
This option is available to you in all three: intraday, BTST, and long-term.
So, I hope you understand how
you can manage
your MTF with money.  You can do your intraday, swing
or long term trading. If
this video was helpful, give a thumbs up
and subscribe to my channel.
Thank you, bye bye.